Now it is time to talk to our management
and the results of
general insurance company
ICICI Lombard were not good in the third quarter i.e. Quarter 3.   The
company's profit has decreased by 9%.
However, if you look at the net premium, there has been a
slight increase.  But
how do we interpret these results further and what are the future growth plans
?  To discuss this, we have with us
Gopal Balachandran, CFO of ICICI LBR.
Gopal ji, hello, good morning and
welcome. First of all, best
wishes to you on Makar Sankranti. Sir, my question to you is that
how were the quarter three numbers according to you and the way we have
seen momentum in auto sales, will we
see growth in this regard? So
first of all, Seasons Greetings to you, to all your
CNBC staff and to all your
viewers, from our side on behalf of
ICBC, Hearty Seasons Greetings. Now coming back to
your question on growth
and how was our quarter three
performance, I would like to explain it in context. The
philosophy of ICS Labad has been always to kind of
drive
profitable growth and this has been our philosophy,
this is what has got exhibited in the
quarter three numbers and as I had
said last time also that the growth momentum
on the ground has been seeing is kind of
looking very, very positive.  If you remember
last quarter, around the end of the
quarter, there have been various
reforms that were kind of put into
existence.  Morantly the GST which was
a landmark reform that was done.
Because of that, sentiments on the ground have been
very positive across the key lines of
businesses that we rightly call our organization.
And I want to talk about each segment.
For example, if we talk about motors,
ICICI LBA has always maintained market leadership in motors.
And if you see, the
growth of IC LB in this first half was
much less than the growth of the industry.  There was
a gap of almost about 500 basis
points.  But in quarter three we have narrowed that gap
down considerably.  And
monetarily in the month of December, the
growth in motor insurance by IC Labrador has been better than
the industry growth by all
Mr. Gopal, but my question to you is
because you were talking about motor insurance, you said that the
underwriting losses in motor insurance have
increased a bit.  Why is that and do you
see it decreasing?
So as I said,
when we look at the outcome of the absolute amount, it has to be always seen in
line with the
accounting prescription.
Whenever there is growth in any quarter, if you
see better growth, the current
existing accounting prescription
says that the earnings of your premium which you
will underwrite in quarter three will happen
over a period of the
next 12 months, but whatever cost you will
incur for cost of sourcing, the entire
cost has to be taken upfront.  So, in
whichever quarter you
see better growth, on an
absolute basis, your underwriting
number in that quarter will be an adverse number.   Is.
That's why we always say that the
numbers you need to look at have to be either
the combined ratio of the segment and
moreover the return on equity which
I talked about earlier is something that we will be kind
of monitoring it very very closely.
So absolute underwriting is
purely a function of growth and as
I said, IC
Labard has seen very good growth in this quarter three.  And
in the month of December, as I said, we have had an
outperformance in motor by more than
400 basis points and since
you talked about underwriting, let me
tell you that the combined ratio of the industry,
we have the numbers of the first half,
based on public disclosure, the
combined ratio of the industry and motor has actually become
much more adverse, there has been a movement of combined ratio from 124% to 128%,
motor
combined ratios for the industry,
if we look at the combined ratio of IC LBA in this half year, there has actually been an
improvement.
Our combined ratio in the last half year was
around 108%.  And in the current half year
our combined ratio is about 117%.
So Hans, we've seen improvements
in our motor combined ratio.  But the industry
combined ratio is actually vat.  So once again we have
continued to stay with our
philosophy of driving profitable growth.
Ok.  So Gopal ji, are you looking at the motor insurance rate
revision?
We have 100% expectation because you are
talking in the context of motor third party reference.  So since this has been an
area where it has not tried much,
in general, the overall industry has been kind of
working with the government and the insurance
regulator because almost for the last
three-four years, if you have noticed, there has not been
a meaningful
change as far as third party rates are
concerned, but in the third party claim
awards which come through the courts,
we have seen that there is
definitely an increase in claim compensation.
So since there is every reason for a third
party price increase to happen, we will wait for
it to be notified.  If it comes then
accordingly we will be able to kind of talk more
specific about it.
Ok.  All right.  Thank you very much Gopal ji for
joining us today.  Thank you for answering all the questions
so well and all the very
best for the upcoming quarters.
[Music] Please
note that the views expressed on Money Control are the
personal views of the experts.   The
website or management is not responsible for this.
Money Control advises users to
seek advice from certified experts before taking any investment decisions.